麦琪:还没有迈克的消息吗?我要去报警.
Maggie: Still no sign of Mike? I'm going to call the police.
杰森:你说什么?现在是凌晨三点,
Jason: And what are you going to say?
我们18岁的儿子还没有回家?
It's three am and our 18 year old son isn't home yet?
麦琪:你说对了,说对了,上帝还让他进了大学.
Maggie: Your right, your right, he's in junior college for god's sakes.
杰森:对的,他不再是个孩子了.
Jason: That's right. It's not like he's a baby anymore.
麦琪,如果你不去报警的话,
Maggie, if you are not going to call the police , I will.
我去.你知道我真的认为这一切都是因我而起
You know I really thought all this was behind us now...and...
迈克:你们好.
Mike: Hi guys.
杰森和麦琪:你好,迈克 迈克????
Jason and Maggie: Hi Mike...MIKE????
杰森:等一下,你去哪儿了?现在应该去学校.
Jason: Wait a minute, where have you been? It's a school night.
麦琪:我们被你吓倒了.
Maggie: We were terrified something happened to you.
迈克:什么也没发生 晚安.
Mike: Well, nothing did... Good night.
杰森:迈克,坐……过来,
Jason: Mike, sit... Come on,
我们想知道自从上次课之后,你去哪儿了.
we want to know where you've been since your last class.
迈克:好的,我很抱歉.
Mike: All right, I'm sorry, I didn't plan on being this late.
我没打算这么晚的.车坏了,这可不是我的错.
It's not my fault that the lift broke.
杰森:好,我们不管谁犯了错.什么车?
Jason: Look, we don't care who's fault....What lift?
迈克:哦,滑雪车.
Mike: Oh the ski lift.
麦琪:你们为什么会在滑雪车上?
Maggie: Why were you on a ski lift?
迈克:你想让我怎么办,妈妈?步行上雪山?
Mike: Well what would you want me to do mom? Walk up the ski slopes?
杰森:我们希望你大学的时候在阿尔卑斯山上,不是雪山,
Jason: We want you to be on Alps land in junior college mike, not on slopes.
什么雪山?
What slopes?
迈克:哦,那有区别吗,爸爸?
Mike: Oh come on, does it really matter dad?
麦琪:是的,你去了哪儿?
Maggie: Yes, where did you go?
迈克:北部.
Mike: North.
杰森:更具体一些,迈克.
Jason: We'd like a little more to go on, Mike.
迈克:好吧,我去了普拉茨德湖.
Mike: Ok, I went to Lake Placid.
麦琪:迈克,普拉茨德湖离这超过两百里.
Maggie: Mike, lake placid is over two hundred miles away.
迈克:这是我晚的另一个理由.你们想让我做什么?
Mike: Which is another reason why I'm so late.
收到一张超速罚单?
What do you guys want me to do? Get a speeding ticket?
杰森:好了,迈克.
Jason: All right, let's cut the tap dance Mike...
迈克:爸爸……一切都很好,
Mike: Dad, dad, dad...
我在大学里,
all right look, I was at college,
和另外两个家伙讨论哲学,
and me and a couple of the other guys were hanging out at "landonware"
以及他们在雪季第一次去普拉茨德湖时的舢板.
discussing philosophy and junk like that when somebody mentioned that
因为我下午没课,
they got the first seasons snow on lake placid.
所以我们决定……
So since I didn't have an afternoon class, we decided to...
杰森:你星期三有社会学课.
Jason: You have sociology on Wednesdays.
迈克:不,
Mike: No no no, I dropped that duffus class weeks ago.
不不,我几个星期前放弃了这门课,
So anyway, I'm on my way up the lift for the last run of the day
所以我是在回家前的最后一节课后去了雪山.
before we head home and boom.
整个的雪情很严重,
This whole snowman just falls on the tow chain,
把我们捆在了半山腰,因此我进退两难,
and it stops us dead halfway up the mountain.
似乎只有被冻死的份了.
So there I am stranded, facing the very real possibility of freezing to death.
麦琪:你放弃了社会学.
Maggie: You dropped sociology.
迈克:是的,所以……
Mike: Yeah, so...
杰森:你认为你现在是大学生了,就可以想做什么就能做什么,
Jason: And you think that now your in college, you can do whatever you like,
来去自由.我没问题了.
come and go whenever you like, no questions asked.
迈克:太好了.
Mike: Pretty much, yeah.
杰森:现在能指望你五个小时以后清醒地去上经济学课程吗?
Jason: Now how do you expect to be awake for economics in 5 hours?
迈克:爸爸,我不是你所想的不负责任,
Mike: Dad, I'm not nearly as irresponsible as you think.
只是如此从凑巧,我也放弃了那门课.所以无论如何……
It just so happens that I dropped that class too. So anyway...
麦琪:你放弃了两门课,却不告诉我们?
Maggie: So you dropped two classes, without even telling us?
迈克:妈妈,我不想隐瞒你.
Mike: Mom, its not like I'm keeping it from you.
我的意思是,嘿,
I mean hey, college doesn't mind if I drop a class here or there.
大学里不介意我是否放弃一门课.爸爸,甚至有一个教授告诉我,
Dad, I even have got a professor who told me if I didn't care about his
如果我对他的课不感兴趣,可以不用来.
class, don't come.
杰森:好,你被关禁闭了.
Jason: That's it, you're grounded.
迈克:我怎么了?
Mike: I'm what?
杰森:禁闭,记住,禁闭?没有约会,没有聚会,没有生活.
Jason: Grounded. Remember, grounded? No dates, no parties, no life.
迈克:爸爸,你不能关一个18岁大学生的禁闭.
Mike: Dad, you cannot ground an 18 year old college man.
杰森:我没有.我只是关一个18岁的滑雪笨蛋.
Jason: I'm not, I'm grounding an 18 year old ski bomb.
迈克:不,爸爸,禁闭只能用于小孩子.
Mike: But dad, grounding is for kids.
杰森:事实上你就是.
Jason: Well that's exactly what you are.
迈克:妈妈,你能相信他对我说什么了吗?
Mike: Mom could you believe he just said that to me?
我,是一个已经足够为国效力的成年人.
To me, a guy old enough to die for his country.
麦琪:也许他应该早就如此.
Maggie: Maybe sooner than he thinks.
迈克:我不明白,这究竟怎么回事?
Mike: I don't get this, what the heck is going on around here?
杰森:我们只想让你表现得像一个成年人,迈克.
Jason: We just want you to behave like the adult that you are Mike.
迈克:哦,你现在承认我是一个成年人.
Mike: Oh so now you admit that im an adult.
杰森:是的,我只是按照你的说法.
Jason: Well, let me put it to you this way, all right?
只要你住在这里,你就得按我的规矩办.
As long as you live under this roof, you live under my rules
麦琪:我们的规矩.
Maggie: Our rules.
杰森:对.
Jason: Yes.
迈克:好了,也许我不会再住在这个屋檐下.
Mike: Well, then, fine, then maybe I won't live under this roof.
杰森:很好.
Jason: Fine.
迈克:很好.
Mike: Fine.
杰森:很好.
Jason: Fine.
迈克:很好,从明天开始.
Mike: Fine, starting tomorrow.
迈克:想一下,本,爸爸的主要弱点是什么?
Mike: Think about it Ben, what is dad's major weakness?
本:昂贵的理发花费.
Ben: Expensive haircuts?
迈克:不不不,我是说主要的.
Mike: No no no, I said major.
本:嗯……妈妈!
Ben: Uhh...Mom!
迈克:对!看,妈妈不想让我出去挨冻,这会让爸爸屈服.我相信连一个晚上的时间都不用花.实际上如果妈妈让我走出这个大门,我会很吃惊的.然后爸爸会求我留下来.
Mike: Right. See, mom will send me out there freezing and get dad to cave in. I bet it wouldn't even take a whole night. In fact I'd be surprised if mom even lets me get out the front door. And then dad will beg me to stay, on my terms.
本:喔.
Ben: Wow.
迈克:如果我现在不斗争的话,爸爸就会一辈子像对待小孩子一样对待我,
Mike: If I don't take a stand now, dad is just going to treat me like a kid my whole life.
杰森:如果我们现在妥协,他会永远像个小孩子.
Jason: Look, if we don't take a stand now, he will act like a kid his whole life
麦琪:杰森,你难道不过分吗?
Maggie: Jason, aren't you being a tad irrational?
杰森:你怎么能这样说?
Jason: How could you say that?
麦琪:好,你想过这样会伤害本和开萝尔吗?
Maggie: Ok well have you thought about how this could traumatize Ben and Carol?
开萝尔:我去布置餐桌.
Carol: I'm going to set the dinner table.
麦琪:谢谢你,开萝尔!
Maggie: Thank you Carol.
开萝尔:我可以坐在迈克坐的位置上吗,现在他已经是历史了?
Carol: Can I sit where Mike used to sit, now that's he's history?
杰森:当然,为什么不?
Jason: Sure, why not?
开萝尔:太好了.
Carol: Great.
杰森:开萝尔看起来很能忍耐.
Jason: Carol seems to be bearing up rather well.
麦琪:杰森,他在哪儿?
Maggie: Jason where will he live?
杰森:我告诉你,麦琪,这里!他现在还在猪圈里.
Jason: I will tell you Maggie, Here! In the same pig sty of a room he lives in now.
麦琪:我听不懂.
Maggie: I'm not following this at all.
杰森:听着,我不想让他搬走,他也不想搬走,他想吓唬我们,麦琪.杰森?西维尔可是一个打牌的高手.
Jason: Look, I don't want him to move out, and he doesn't want to move out either. He's trying to bluff us Maggie, and I'm going to call his bluff. Jason Seaver is one savvy poker player.
迈克:好吧,本,你送我到大门.
Mike: Sure, Ben you can walk me to the front door.
杰森:我们需要在这个问题联合起来,你同意吗?
Jason: We need to present a united front on this one, agreed?
麦琪:好,好,好.
Maggie: Yeah yeah yeah.
迈克:我想我得和你说再见.
Mike: Well, I guess I will be seeing you.
杰森:再见.
Jason: Guess so.
开萝尔:餐桌布置好了.哦,爸爸,我想把迈克的房间改造成健身房,行吗?
Carol: Table is all set. Oh dad, will it also be ok if I turn Mike's room into an exercise room?
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:好主意,宝贝.
Jason: That's a good idea honey.
开萝尔:谢谢.
Carol: Thanks.
迈克:你至少也得体面地等我走了以后.
Mike: You can at least have the decency to wait until the body is cold.
开萝尔:生活还得继续.
Carol: Life goes on.
杰森:迈克,你有以后的地址吗?
Jason: Mike, you have a forwarding address?
迈克:有,BLA 523.
Mike: Uh yeah, BLA 523.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
迈克:我的驾照号码.
Mike: My license plate.
麦琪:你说什么?
Maggie: Pardon me?
迈克:是的,妈妈,我要住在车里了.
Mike: Yes mother, I'm going to live in my vehicle.
麦琪:杰森,他要住在车里.
Maggie: Jason, he's going to live in his vehicle.
杰森:好,我相信你的车不会停在我的车道上.
Jason: Well I trust your vehicle won't be parked in my driveway.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:好,搬出去,和这房子脱离关系.
Jason: Well, moving out, generally means off the premises.
麦琪:杰森,事情有点过了.
Maggie: Jason this thing has gone too far.
杰森:麦琪?
Jason: Maggie?
麦琪:不,迈克.你可以住在你的车里,在我的车道上.
Maggie: No, Mike...You can live in your car, on my half of the driveway.
迈克:谢谢.卧室,娱乐室,我可爱的家.
Mike: Thanks. Living room, Robus room, home sweet home.
开萝尔:外面很冷.
Carol: Boy is it freezing out here.
迈克:谢谢你告诉我这鬼天气,开萝尔,出去.
Mike: Thank you Carol for that startling weather bulletin. Get out.
开萝尔:迈克,你以为我不知道你在做什么吗?
Carol: Mike, don't you think I know what you are doing?
迈克:开萝尔,你知道你自己在做什么吗?
Mike: Carol, I don't even think you know what you are doing.
开萝尔:你根本没打算搬出去,你不过是想住在这里让爸爸内疚,然后回去而已.
Carol: You have no intention of moving out, you just want to guilt dad by living here and good off.
迈克:你真的不了解我,开萝尔?现在你给我走.
Mike: You really don't know me at all do you Carol? Now get out.
开萝尔:听着!我同意把一个大学生像小孩子那样关禁闭是愚蠢的.一个18岁的成年人应该有来去自由的权利,只要他愿意.
Carol: Look, I agree that it's silly for a college student to be grounded like some child. An 18 year old should feel free to come and go as he or she pleases.
迈克:我懂了.你站在我这边,并不是因为我是你的哥哥而关心我,而是因为你明年也要18岁了,你也要由着性子来.
Mike: Hold on I get it. So you aren't on my side because I'm your brother and you care about me. But because you turn 18 next year and you want to grease the track for your self.
开萝尔:你也完全不了解我.
Carol: You really don't know me at all do you?
迈克:开萝尔,你的自私令我恶心.
Mike: Carol your selfishness sickens me.
开萝尔:你会懂的.我们都想让爸爸给你自由,这是所有18岁的成人应得的,我可以帮你.这里有一些好吃的,给你补充点能量.
Carol: You will get over it. The point is that we both have an interest in getting dad to give you the kind of freedom that all 18 year olds so richly deserve, and I can help. Here's some tasty treats to help keep your strength up.
迈克:开萝尔,这些还冻着呢.
Mike: Carol, these are still frozen.
开萝尔:发动一下汽车,把它放在发动机上,20分钟后,你就有热馄饨吃了.记住,我站在你这一边,至少在精神上.
Carol: Just start your car, set it on the engine and in 20 minutes you got hot ravioli. And just remember, I'm with you on this. In spirit, anyway.
杰森:外面很冷.有什么事情我要知道吗?
Jason: It's cold out there. Anything going on in the world I should know about?
麦琪:一个十来岁的孩子被无知的父亲驱逐,冻死了,11点的电影.
Mom: Teenage boy banished by juvenile father freezes, film at 11.
杰森:无知?麦琪,我是一个受过良好训练的心理健康师,毕业于正规医学院.每个人都可以赞成或者反对我的做法,但是不可以说我是无知.
Jason: Juvenile? Well Maggie I am a highly trained mental health practitioner schooled in the complexities of the adolescent psyche. Now one may agree or disagree with my strategy but I am being anything but juvenile.
电视:天气预报,今晚长岛将有一场大雪.
TV: The weather service is calling for a major snowfall in long island tonight
杰森:好!!
Jason: Yes!!
麦琪:我去楼上看书.
Maggie: I'm going upstairs to read.
杰森:麦琪.这儿的农民们需要这场雪.
Jason: Maggie...Come on, I meant the farmers here they need the snow.
麦琪:农民们?
Maggie: The farmers?
杰森:我们这地区有旱情,我想我们应该更多地考虑大家的利益,而不是我们自己.
Jason: Well there is a drought going on in this country Megan, I think we have to be concerned with people with bigger problems than our own.
麦琪:你这么干吧.
Maggie: You do that.
杰森:"你好,雪",迈克在做什么呢?
Jason: "Hello snow" What does he think he's doing anyway?
迈克:哦,喔,下雪了!好,来得正好,我能应付得了.
Mike: Oh wow, snow! All right. I got them right where I want them. Who does he think he's dealing with anyway?
迈克:时候差不多了
Mike: Ah...it's about time...
麦琪:外面冷死了.
Maggie: It's freezing out here.
迈克:如果你让我进去,我就进去.
Mike: Oh well if you insist mom I guess I'll come inside.
麦琪:不,你不能进来.
Maggie: No, you can't come inside.
迈克:不?我只是很想你,妈妈.
Mike: No? Well I was only thinking of you mom.
麦琪:你饿吗,迈克?
Maggie: Are you hungry Mike?
迈克:哦,不.天太冷,嚼不动.
Mike: Oh no, it's too cold to chew.
麦琪:你说真的?
Maggie: Are you sure?
迈克:是的,哦,妈妈,你来这儿了,你最好进屋去,要不然你会冻死的.告诉爸爸,我很好.
Mike: Yeah, oh mom here. You better go inside. You'll catch your death. Oh, and tell dad that I will be fine.
麦琪:我不会告诉你爸爸,我到了外面.我就想告诉你,车库顶上的储藏室里有一个取暖器.
MOM: I can't tell your father I'm out here. I just want to tell you that there is a space heater in the storage room above the garage.
迈克:但是这会用爸爸的电.这可不行,不过还是谢谢你.
Mike: Oh but that would be using dads electricity. And that would be so wrong, but thanks anyway.
麦琪:好的,迈克,你随便怎么做吧.
Maggie: well Mike, you do what you have to do.
迈克:工作就像魔咒.
Mike: Working like a charm.
杰森:加油,迈克,理智些.宝宝怎么样了?
Jason: Come on Mike, have some sense. So how's the baby?
麦琪:冻死了.
Maggie: Freezing.
杰森:冻死了?
Jason: Freezing?
麦琪:我没有说冻死,我是说很好.
Maggie: I didn't mean freezing I meant fine.
杰森:她的房间里要是下雪的话,肯定会冻死.
Jason: No wonder she is freezing, it's snowing in her room.
麦琪:好了,我出去看迈克了.你骂我吧.
Maggie: All right, so I went out to check on Mike. So sue me.
杰森:宝贝,我也关心迈克,这点和你一样,但是他得接受教训,你知道,迈克……他很难吸取教训.
Jason: Honey I'm just as concerned about Mike as you are but he's got an important lesson to learn here, and you know Mike...he doesn't learn easy.
麦琪:我知道,他的牛脾气和他爸一样.
Maggie: I know, he's bull headed like his father.
杰森:你指什么?难道是我们让他逃学吗?等他到了四十岁,我们还得替他交罚单?他会去抢劫便利店,然后被捕.你有时间打官司吗,你有小宝宝,你还得工作.
Jason: Oh so what do you suggest? We just let him blow college? He will be forty years old, we will still be buying his lifts tickets. He will start knocking over convenient stores, get arrested. Do you have time for a trial, what with the new baby and work and all?
麦琪:杰森,你说的很好听.我同意我们应该惩罚一下他,但是你不能对他真诚些吗?你何必要骗他?
Maggie: Jason, you are being a whacko. Now I agree that we have to get him straightened out, but can't you just be honest with him? Do you have to trick him?
杰森:我们必须让迈克知道,无论在哪里都不能犯错,我们不能再等待了.
Jason: Well we have to send Mike a message. This is it. Make no mistake where you are, this is it, the waiting is over.
麦琪:你是在按多比兄弟的那首歌办事?
Maggie: You are basing your action on a song by the Doobie brothers?
杰森:不.
Jason: No.
麦琪:我希望不是.
Maggie: Well I hope not.
杰森:那是肯妮?罗金作的曲,迈克尔?多纳德演唱,很多人以为是多比兄弟的唱片,实际上并不是.
Jason: That is a Kenny Login's tune. Michael o Donald's sang on it, so a lot of people think it was a Doobie brother's record, but no.
麦琪:杰森!!!
Maggie: Jason!!!
杰森:好吧,我和他谈谈.
Jason: Ok, all right, I'll talk to him.
麦琪:事实上,那时肯妮?罗金作的词.
Maggie: Actually, it's a Kenny Login's tune.
杰森:迈克?我只是想看看你好不好?好的,你知道你是个牛脾气,就像你妈.我们俩停火,怎么样?你愿意进屋和我谈谈吗?我看见你在我前面,哦,上帝!!!
Jason: Mike? I just want to be sure you are ok. Ok, fine...you know you are bull-headed, just like your mother. Look, how about we call it a cease-fire ok? How about he go inside and talk about it.... I see you are way ahead of me. OH GOD!!!
迈克:爸爸,我们沟通过了.
Mike: Dad I thought we had an understanding.
杰森:你不能住在我的屋檐下.
Jason: You can't live under my roof.
迈克:但是,但是我只是……
Mike: But dad I was just...
杰森:好啊,我一直都很担心你在大雪中……现在你在这儿,看着电视,温暖如春,不用关心外面的世界.
Jason: Oh and I was all worried about you out in the snow...and now you are here, you got the TV blasting, warm as toast, you don't have a care in the world.
迈克:爸爸,几分钟前我还在外面呢,又冷又饿,孤苦伶仃.
Mike: Well dad, I wasn't up until a minute ago, I was outside, cold and lonely and hungry.
伙计:比萨.
Guy: Pizza.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
迈克:爸爸,我可没订比萨.
Mike: Dad I did not order that pizza.
杰森:你以为我会替你付钱,那你就是在做梦.
Jason: Well if you think I'm paying for that you are nuts.
伙计:嘿,放松点,麦琪?西维尔已经付过了.
Guy: Hey relax pal, it's already paid for by Maggie Seaver.
杰森:麦琪?西维尔,那不合适……迈克,马上进去.
Jason: Maggie Seaver, well doesn't that just fit...Mike get inside right now.
迈克:爸爸,我……
Mike: Dad I...
伙计:嘿,你们不想要了吗?我告诉你们已经付过了,小费很不错.
Guy: Well hey don't you want it? I told you it's already paid for...nice tip.
杰森:好了,迈克,我们直截了当来说吧.
Jason: All right Mike, why don't we just lay out all our cards on the table now.
迈克:好的.
Mike: Fine.
杰森:好的.
Jason: Fine.
麦琪:你们两个就这么好的,好的,没完没了吗?
Maggie: Are you two going to go through this fine-fine business again?
杰森:这是你的比萨.
Jason: Here's your pizza.
麦琪:杰森,天太冷了,他看起来又这么饿.
Maggie: Jason it was so cold, and he looked so hungry.
杰森:好的,我现在担心的最后一件事不是比萨.
Jason: Well the last thing I'm worried about right now is pizza.
本:什么比萨?
Ben: What pizza?
麦琪:本,不关你的事,回去睡觉.
Maggie: Ben this doesn't concern you, go to bed.
本:迈克还在外面吗?
Ben: Is Mike still kicked out?
杰森:迈克没有被驱逐.
Jason: Mike is not kicked out.
本:那么他成功了
Ben: Then It worked.
杰森:什么成功了?
Jason: What worked?
本:哦,没事,当然这不是迈克的计划.
Ben: Um nothing, certainly not Mike's plan.
杰森:迈克,你别想骗任何人,我不是傻瓜.我知道你没想过住在车里,你只是争取同情,让我屈服.
Jason: Mike you are not fooling anybody, I'm not stupid. I know you didn't intend to live in your car; you were just putting on that pathetic little act so that I cave in.
迈克:不,爸爸,我不会使用屈服这个词.
Mike: Well no dad, I would not use the term cave in.
开萝尔:你们在吵什么呢?你们把宝宝吵醒了.
Carol: What's all this shouting about? You guys are going to wake the baby.
麦琪:开萝尔,我们在和你的哥哥讨论事,你介意吗?
Maggie: Carol, we are having a discussion with your brother, do you mind?
开萝尔:完全可以.哦,在我上楼之前我想说些话.
Carol: Not in the least. Oh, well, before I go upstairs I want to say something.
麦琪:说吧,开萝尔?
Maggie: what is it Carol?
开萝尔:实际上,我看见迈克离开这房子,我很兴奋,我相信18岁的人法律上应该拥有某种不可剥夺的权力,这些是……
Carol: Well actually, as delighted as I am to see Mike out of my house, I do believe that 18 year olds is legally endowed with certain undeniable rights, and among these are...
杰森:你想知道我相信什么吗,开萝尔?
Jason: You want to know what I believe Carol?
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
杰森:我相信你并不介意迈克的权力,你只关心明年你18岁后,你所考虑的个人自由,我说的不错吧?
Jason: I believe that you are not so concerned about Mike's rights as you are about t the fact that you are going to turn 18 next year and you're thinking about your personal freedom, now am I getting warm?
开萝尔:你一点也不了解我.
Carol: You really don't know me at all do you?
麦琪:晚安,开萝尔.
Maggie: Good night Carol.
迈克:很顺利,真的很顺利.
Mike: Smooth, real smooth.
杰森:好的,我们说到哪了?
Jason: All right where were we?
麦琪:你刚才说迈克在演戏,你知道,打牌的老手也在做同样的事情.
Maggie: Oh you were just saying that Mike was putting on an act, you know, sort of the same thing the old savvy poker player was doing?
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:好吧,我承认,我不想让你搬走,迈克,没有人想让你搬走.
Jason: Ok I admit it; I didn't want you to move out Mike, anymore than you wanted to move.
麦琪:终于说实话了.
Maggie: Finally the truth.
杰森:我只是不能容忍,大学第一年就虚度光阴,逃课,跳华尔兹跳到很晚,只要你乐意,让你妈妈和我担心你每天晚上会在哪儿.
Jason: I just couldn't bare to watch you just fritter away your first year in college. Dropping classes left and right or walcing in and out as late as you please, and making your mother and I worried sick about where you are every night.
迈克:首先,我没有虚度光阴,懂吗?我只是稍微调整了一下我的课程,我没有在这跳华尔兹,我甚至不知道什么是华尔兹.
Mike: Well first of all, I did not fritter, ok? I merely fined tuned my class schedule. And and I did not walce in here, I don't even know how to walce.
杰森:我受不了你这样的态度,迈克.
Jason: I can't live with you like this Mike.
迈克:我也受不了你的愚蠢规定,自从我刚学会走路就一直没有改变过.
Mike: And I can't live with your stupid rules because they haven't changed since I have been a toddler.
杰森:你不改变,它们也不会改变.
Jason: And they won't until you change.
迈克:那很好.
Mike: Well fine
杰森:很好.
Jason: Fine.
麦琪:太好了,现在我们回家说很好吧.两头牛,没有一个愿意承认对方哪怕有一点道理,杰森,这个问题上我们需要统一.
Maggie: Great, now we are back to fine. I mean 2 bull headed know-it-alls, staring each other down, neither one willing to admit that the other one just might have a point. Jason, we need to present a united front on this one.
杰森:好了,也许对于你这么大的人,关禁闭是不合适的.
Jason: All right, uh, maybe it's not appropriate for someone your age to be grounded.
迈克:的确如此,那是我一直想说的.
Mike: Exactly, that's what I have been trying to say all along....what?
麦琪:该轮到你让一步了.
Maggie: No it's your turn to concede a point.
迈克:妈妈,我没有什么要让的.好,也许没告诉你们我在哪儿,让你们担心,是我不对.
Mike: Mom, I have nothing to concede...Ok, maybe scaring you guys by not telling you where I was, was a little wrong.
杰森:你说了它是错误的.一个大学生也许应该有一点权力自己做决定.
Jason: You bet it was wrong. And maybe a college man should have a little leeway in making his own decisions.
迈克:我应该在放弃这些课程之前找你商量一下,但是只是听一下你的建议.
Mike: And I guess I could run it by you before I drop classes, but just to hear your advice.
杰森:那正是我要的.
Jason: That's all I ask.
麦琪:现在我们有进展了……看,这样不很好吗?
Maggie: Now we are getting somewhere...see? Isn't this fun?
迈克:我相信你不想让你的儿子在外面挨冻.
Mike: Boy, I sure didn't think you would send your son out there to freeze.
杰森:迈克,我让你在外面挨冻的唯一理由是因为我爱你.
Jason: Mike the only reason I sent you out there to freeze was because I love you.
迈克:真想看到你如何对待一个陌生人.
Mike: Well I'd hate to see how you treat a stranger.
麦琪:迈克……
Maggie: Mike...
杰森:如果一个陌生人搬来这儿,我才不管他去哪,他做了什么,也不管有是否逃学呢.
Jason: Well if a stranger moved in here, I wouldn't care where he went or what he did, or how he screwed up his education.
麦琪:哦,杰森.
Maggie: Oh Jason.
迈克:哦,如果一个陌生人搬到这儿,你不会指望他遵守你愚蠢的规定.
Mike: Oh yeah, well if a stranger moved in here, you wouldn't expect him to live by your stupid rules either.
杰森:不,但是我指望他付给我房租.
Jason: No, but I'd expect him to pay rent then.
迈克:好,他也不会被关禁闭.
Mike: Well, beats the heck out of being grounded.
杰森:你这样想吗?
Jason: Oh you think so?
麦琪:哦,等一下,等一下.你说了什么?
Maggie: Oh wait a minute, wait a minute. What did you say?
迈克:他不会给关禁闭.
Mike: Beats the heck out of being grounded.
麦琪:不,不,,不是你.是你!
Maggie: No, no no not you. You!
杰森:你这样想?哦,麦琪,你咋样?
Jason: Oh you think so? Oh Maggie what's with you?
麦琪:你说如果一个陌生人搬过来,你会让他付房租.而你说如果一个陌生人搬过来,你爸不会要求他遵守这些愚蠢的规定.
Maggie: You said that if a stranger moved in that you'd expect him to pay rent. And you said that if a stranger moved in, he wouldn't be expected to live by your dad's stupid rules.
杰森:愚蠢的规定?
Jason: Stupid rules?
麦琪:我只是引用而已.但是,亲爱的,我们可以有一个解决办法了.
Maggie: I was just quoting. But the point is, honey, we may have stumbled on to a solution.
迈克:好的.那是什么?
Mike: Yeah, what is it?
杰森:哦!
Jason: OH!!!
麦琪:喔!
Maggie: Uh huh!
杰森:麦琪,也许你真的有办法.
Jason: Maggie, maybe you are on to something
迈克:太好了,说吧.
Mike: Great, tell me what it is.
麦琪:这会帮助你们两个彼此建立一种新的关系.
Maggie: It would help the two of you look at each other in a whole new light.
迈克:什么关系?
Mike: What light?
杰森:只要那不是象征性的.
Jason: As long as it's not just symbolic.
迈克:我回房间.
Mike: I am in the room here.
麦琪:你的意思呢?
Maggie: What do you mean?
迈克:好.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:好,你妈妈在建议你付给我房租.
Jason: Well, your mother is suggesting that you pay us rent.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yes.
迈克:你这样对待我,还要我付房租?
Mike: What you want me to pay to be treated like this?
杰森:不,你付了,就可以享受陌生人的待遇.
Jason: No no, you pay to be treated like a stranger.
麦琪:那实际上不是我的意思.
Maggie: That's not exactly what I meant.
迈克:哦,所以你们不会再管我了?
Mike: Oh so you guys couldn't get on my case about anything.
麦琪:我可没这么说.
Maggie: I didn't say that.
杰森:不确切.它意味着我们得签订一个租赁合同,如果你违反了,你就拍屁股走人吧.
Jason: Not exactly. It means we strike up a rental agreement, and if you violate that you are out on your keester.
迈克:但是如果我没有违反,你们不能那样说?
Mike: But if I didn't violate it you guys couldn't say anything right?
麦琪:不,我可没说
Maggie: No I know I didn't say that...
迈克:好吧,妈妈,你的主意真不赖.
Mike: Ok, mom this idea of yours is going to work out great.
麦琪:真有趣,我不记得我出了这主意.
Maggie: Funny, I don't remember thinking of it.
杰森:不,这样可行.
Jason: No, this could work.
麦琪:杰森,我不明白……你原来说"只要住在这个屋檐下,就得遵守你的规定"?
Maggie: Jason, I don't get you...I mean what ever happened to "as long as you live under this roof, you live by our rules?"
迈克:是的.
Mike: Oh yeah.
杰森:麦琪,我们正在解决问题,我们不需要你来唱反调.
Jason: Maggie, we are trying to work something out here, we don't need your negative energy.
迈克:不,爸爸,你知道车库上的储藏室吗?技术上讲它不在这个屋檐下.
Mike: No dad, you know that storage room above the garage? Technically that is not under this roof.
杰森:好主意.
Jason: Good thinking.
麦琪:等一下.我不能让我的儿子住在车库里.
Maggie: Wait a minute. I am not sending my son to live in a garage.
迈克:不,妈妈,我会把它改造成一套标准公寓.
Mike: No mom I will just fix it up like a regular apartment.
本:使用"快乐"基金.
Ben: It worked for the Funds on "happiness"
麦琪:好,好.
Maggie: Ok. ok...
迈克:爸爸,你要我付多少钱?
Mike: SO dad, how much would you charge me for this room?
杰森:最少75.
Jason: 75 minimum.
迈克:就这么个储藏室?
Mike: For that dump?
杰森:好吧,60.
Jason: Ok, 60.
迈克:20.
Mike: 20.
杰森:60.
Jason: 60
迈克:30.
Mike: 30
杰森:60.
Jason: 60
迈克:50.
Mike: 50
杰森:成交.
Jason: Done.
迈克:好的,外加一日三餐.
Mike: Fine, plus meal privileges.
杰森:如果你准时的话.
Jason: If you are on time.
迈克:没问题.
Mike: No problem.
杰森:你要洗碗……
Jason: And do dishes...
迈克:一星期一次.
Mike: Once a week.
杰森:两次.
Jason: twice.
迈克:好吧,这房间不允许你们进来.
Mike: Oh ok, and the room is off limits to parents?
杰森:还有女孩.
Jason: And girls.
迈克:哦,爸爸……
Mike: Oh dad...
杰森:别拖泥带水的了.
Jason: No slack on that one.
迈克:好,没有女孩,只有男的……你知道我说什么.
Mike: All right no girls I will only have men over....You know what I mean.
杰森:好的,现在我们有了一种全新的关系:房东和房客.
Jason: Well, now. We have a whole new relationship here: Landlord-tenant.
迈克:是的,就是这样.
Mike: Yeah, that's what we have.
杰森:我们说定了.
Jason: So we have an agreement.
迈克:说定了.
Mike: We sure do.
杰森:宝贝,你想认识一下新房客吗,这是迈……
Jason: Honey id like you to meet out new tenant, this is Mr....
迈克:西维尔.
Mike: Seaver.
杰森:西维尔.真巧,我是西维尔医生.
Jason: Seaver. What a coincidence I'm Dr. Seaver.
迈克:这位非常迷人的年轻女士是……
Mike: And this incredibly attractive young lady is...
麦琪:别闹着玩了.你们两个至少应该握一下手,而不是互相争吵.
Maggie: Not amused. But at least the two of you are shaking hands instead of acting like raving idiots.
杰森:她赞成这主意.
Jason: She loves this idea.
迈克:很好,这样很好.
Mike: Yeah this is going to work out just fine.
杰森:好的,趁着还没忘记,我们应当把它记下来……现在你想成为合同中的甲方,还是乙方?
Jason: Well since it's fresh in our minds why don't we put it in writing...Now do you want to be the party of the first part, or the party of the second part?
迈克:我不介意,只要有我就行.
杰森:好的,我做甲方吧.不不,这样的引用听起来不太好.所以我们还是先来谈论你的义务吧,迈克?迈克?迈克?
00:22:13,700
Mike: I don't care as long as I'm invited. Jason: All right I will be the party of the first part. No no no, any references to parties would set the wrong tone. So first of all we are going to talk about your obligations, Mike? Mike? Mike?